

AZIZI BIN SHAHARUDDIN

azizishaharuddin@gmail.com | +60172257890 | Linkedin: Azizi Shaharuddin | Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

SUMMARY

A passionate and self-motivated Project Engineer with 1 year working experience in an oil and gas services company. Current scope of work covers every phase of the project which includes (but not limited to) bidding for tender, planning, execution, completion and invoicing. Upon graduating with a Bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering, I enrolled in several online courses to equip myself with programming skills as well as data cleansing and analysis. As of today, I managed to obtain 4 certificates issued by Coursera and I am currently looking to explore new opportunity in the field of data/programming.

Work Experience

TNF ENERGY SDN BHD, Project Engineer

July 2020 - Aug 2021

- Worked closely with the Project Director in managing the projects, ensuring they are conducted according to the project execution plan (PEP) to sustain company's good reputation as well as maintaining good cash flow
- · Prepared weekly progress report (WPR) for progress milestone and finance invoicing to avoid delay in deliverables
- Maintained and monitored project execution on a day-to-day basis
- Liaise with clients, survey and engineering team on resources planning, work progress, issues and mitigation plan
- Reviewed drawings and PDMS Model on Autodesk Navisworks Manage for QAQC purposes
- Reviewed ITB documents, understanding scope of project and prepared all necessary documents for tender submission process
- Assisted the Finance/Accounting department on invoicing and payments to ensure good cash flow and correspond to the Purchase Order (PO) received for every project
- Compiled, sorted all deliverables and final project documentations to meet clients' specifications
- Performed administrative tasks (ie. prepared minutes of meeting, follow up emails, set meeting/review session)
- Managed the renovation project for new office reviewed and coordinated the plan layout, renovation planning, cost, time and resources (CTR) evaluation from the Contractors
- Executed any special task required by Project Director with regards to company's business development

TECNICAIRE SERVICES SDN BHD, Intern (3 months)

Jun 2018 – Aug 2018

- Conducted cleanroom performance test (CPT) to ensure the airflow system and the conditions in the cleanroom are in compliance with specifications based on ISO and grade standards
- Prepared reports and other supporting documents including layout drawing, technical specification and data sheets with reference to the industrial standards

PUTRA PERDANA CONSTRUCTION SDN BHD, Intern (5 months)

Nov 2015 - Mar 2016

- Oversee progress of installation and coordinate with sub-contractors to ensure timely delivery of work
- Assisted engineers to make inspections on the installation of HVAC, mechanical plumbing and lift system to ensure the systems installed operate effectively according to the industrial standard and requirements
- Conducted pressure and leak test to detect any leakage in the ducting/piping system (HVAC and water plumbing)

Education

UNIVERSITI TEKNOLOGI MALAYSIA, JOHOR

2016 - 2019

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical) with Honors

UNIVERSITI TEKNOLOGI MALAYSIA, KUALA LUMPUR

Diploma in Engineering (Mechanical)

2013 - 2016

Projects and Extra Curricular Activities

1. POWER PRODUCTION BY THE INTEGRATED BLADES ON WATER WHEEL, Final Year Project

2019

- Analyzed the effect of integrated blades on the power generated by the water wheel using CFD tool (Ansys)
- Performed design of experiment (DOE) to interpret the correlation between parameters involved and analyzed significant factors contributing to the outcome of the project

2. **LEMONGRASS HARVESTING MACHINE**, Capstone Project

2018

- Performed failure mode & effects analysis (FMEA), root cause & corrective measure analysis, as well as materials requirement
 planning (MRP) to improve cost and utilization of components
- Led the team's presentation in pitching the product to the jury panel.

3. FORMULA STUDENT BOOTCAMP MALAYSIA, Project Director

2017 - 2018

- Led a committee of 30 members in organizing and coordinating an inter-university program, ensuring the smooth success of the program according to the plan
- Developed a comprehensive plan of backup to mitigate the issues raised prior to commencement of the event
- Secured a sponsorship worth of RM 7,000 from various parties/organizations
- Collaborated with Proton, an automotive company, to provide insightful talks regarding Formula race industry in Malaysia
- 4. **FSAE UTM DESTRIER RACING TEAM**, Committee of Sponsorship Department

2017 - 2018

- Conducted research and negotiated with multiple companies to obtain Memorandum of Understanding (MoU)
- Provided a comprehensive overview of the automotive industry market

Additional

Software Skills: Microsoft Office, Microsoft Project, Python, SQL, C/C++, IBM db2, Minitab, Ansys, Navisworks Manage

Languages: Bahasa Malaysia (Native), English (Fluent)

Certificates: Excel Fundamentals for Data Analysis (Macquarie Business School), Introduction to Data Analytics (IBM), Databases &

SQL for Data Science with Python (IBM), Python for Data Science, AI & Development (IBM)

Volunteer: Program Eco-Village Desa Komuniti Dun Kemelah 2018

Reference

1. TENGKU FAIZ TENGKU YUSOFF

Project Director

TNF Energy Sdn Bhd

VSQ@PJCC Block 5-11-3,

Jalan Utara Seksyen 52,

46200 Petaling Jaya, Selangor

Tel: +603 7625 8518

Email: tengku.faiz@tnf-energy.com / info@tnf-energy.com

2. ALICE YONG

Supervisor / Head of Business
TecnicAire Services Sdn Bhd

No 12-1, Jalan PJS 5/28A,

Petaling Jaya City Centre,

46150 Petaling Jaya, Selangor

Tel: +603 7772 8466

Email: tassb09@gmail.com